ques={
       1:{
           'question':"What is the state flower of harayana?",
           'a':'Lotus',
           'b':'Golden shower',
           'c':'Rose',
           'd':'Not declared',
           'ans':'Lotus',
           'marks':1,
           'level':'easy',
           'std':3,
           'sub':'History'
         },
       2:{
           'question':"Which state has the largest population?",
           'a':'Uttar pradesh',
           'b':'Maharashtra',
           'c':'Bihar',
           'd':'Andra pradesh',
           'ans':'Uttar pradesh',
           'marks':1,
           'level':'easy',
           'std':3,
           'sub':'GK'
         },
       3:{
           'question':"Name the first Atomic submarine of India?",
           'a':'I.N.S Chakra',
           'b':'R.N Shukla',
           'c':'V.R Gill',
           'd':'D.B Mahawar',
           'ans':'I.N.S Chakra',
           'marks':1,
           'level':'easy',
           'std':3,
           'sub':'History'
         },
       4:{
           'question':"Name the first Election Comission of India?",
           'a':'Sukumar Sen',
           'b':'R.N Shukla',
           'c':'V.R Gill',
           'd':'D.B Mahawar',
           'ans':'Sukumar Sen',
           'marks':1,
           'level':'easy',
           'std':3,
           'sub':'GK'
         },
       5:{
           'question':"Where is the India's First Nuclear Centre?",
           'a':'Tarapur',
           'b':'Jaipur',
           'c':'Kanpur',
           'd':'Raipur',
           'ans':'Tarapur',
           'marks':1,
           'level':'easy',
           'std':3,
           'sub':'GK'
         },
       6:{
           'question':"Name the first Chinese piligrim to visit India?",
           'a':'Khan Abdul Gaffar Khan ',
           'b':'R.N Shukla',
           'c':'V.R Gill',
           'd':'D.B Mahawar',
           'ans':'Khan Abdul Gaffar Khan',
           'marks':1,
           'level':'easy',
           'std':3,
           'sub':'GK'
         },
       7:{
          'question':'Where were the hymns of Rigveda composed?',
          'a':'Punjab',
          'b':'Gujarat',
          'c':'Rajasthan',
          'd':'Madhya Pradesh',
          'ans':'Punjab',
           'marks':1,
           'level':'easy',
           'std':3,
           'sub':'History'
         },
       8:{
           'question':"Professor Amartya Sen is famous in which of the fields?",
           'a':'Biochemeistry',
           'b':'Electronics',
           'c':'Economics',
           'd':'Gelogy',
           'ans':'Economics',
           'marks':1,
           'level':['easy','medium'],
           'std':[1,2,3],
           'sub':'GK'
         },
       9:{
           'question':"Which of the following organization was not established by BR Ambedkar?",
           'a':'Depressed Classes Institute',
           'b':'Samaj Samata Sangh',
           'c':'Zero Club',
           'd':'People’s Education Society',
           'ans':'Zero Club',
           'marks':1,
           'level':'hard',
           'std':3,
           'sub':'GK'
         },
       10:{
           'question':"Who is the Author of The Name of the Rose?",
           'a':'John Steinbeck',
           'b':'William Shakespeare',
           'c':'Umberto Eco',
           'd':'J K Rowling',
           'ans':'Umberto Eco',
           'marks':1,
           'level':'easy',
           'std':3,
           'sub':'GK'
         },
       11:{
           'question':"The Kandaleru Dam is located in which state?",
           'a':'Andra Pradesh',
           'b':'Kerala',
           'c':'Goa',
           'd':'Agra',
           'ans':'Andra Pradesh',
           'marks':1,
           'level':'easy',
           'std':3,
           'sub':'History'
         },
       12:{
           'question':"The headquarters of Reserve Bank of India is situated in which city?",
           'a':'New Delhi',
           'b':'Lucknow',
           'c':'Mumbai',
           'd':'Agra',
           'ans':'Mumbai',
           'marks':1,
           'level':'easy',
           'std':3,
           'sub':'GK'
         },
       13:{
           'question':"Which of these Indian Footballers is awarded with the Arjuna Award in the year 2019?",
           'a':'Subrata Paul',
           'b':'Pritam Kotal',
           'c':'Gurpreet Singh Sandhu',
           'd':'Sunil Chhetri',
           'ans':'Gurpreet Singh Sandhu',
           'marks':1,
           'level':'easy',
           'std':3,
           'sub':'GK'
         },
       14:{
           'question':"Which one is the smallest ocean in the World?",
           'a':'Indian',
           'b':'Pacific',
           'c':'Atlantic',
           'd':'Arctic',
           'ans':'Arctic',
           'marks':1,
           'level':'easy',
           'std':3,
           'sub':'GK'
         },
       15:{
           'question':"The NOTA option was first used in the elections in?",
           'a':'2013',
           'b':'2010',
           'c':'2005',
           'd':'2012',
           'ans':'2013',
           'marks':1,
           'level':'easy',
           'std':3,
           'sub':'GK'
         },
       16:{
           'question':"Which empire lasted the longest among the following?",
           'a':'Rashtrakutas',
           'b':'Pratiharas',
           'c':'The Palas',
           'd':'The senas',
           'ans':'Rashtrakutas',
           'marks':1,
           'level':'easy',
           'std':3,
           'sub':'GK'
         },
       17:{
           'question':"Who among the following entitled himself as 'Badshah'?",
           'a':'Akbar',
           'b':'Humanyu',
           'c':'Muhammad Babur',
           'd':'None of these',
           'ans':'Muhammad Babur',
           'marks':1,
           'level':'easy',
           'std':3,
           'sub':'GK'
         },
       18:{
           'question':"Akbar sieged Gujarat in …?",
           'a':'1522',
           'b':'1572',
           'c':'1890',
           'd':'2000',
           'ans':'1572',
           'marks':1,
           'level':'easy',
           'std':3,
           'sub':'GK'
         },
       19:{
           'question':"The Sangai Festival is celebrated in?",
           'a':'Manipur',
           'b':'Assam',
           'c':'Kerala',
           'd':'None of these',
           'ans':'Manipur',
           'marks':1,
           'level':'easy',
           'std':3,
           'sub':'History'
         },
       20:{
           'question':"The ratio of width of our National flag to its length is?",
           'a':'1:8',
           'b':'3:5',
           'c':'1:5',
           'd':'2:3',
           'ans':'2:3',
           'marks':1,
           'level':'easy',
           'std':3,
           'sub':'GK'
         },
       21:{
           'question':"In which of the following city Elephant festival is celebrated annually?",
           'a':'Jaipur',
           'b':'Dehradun',
           'c':'Shimla',
           'd':'Chandhighar',
           'ans':'Jaipur',
           'marks':1,
           'level':'easy',
           'std':3,
           'sub':'History'
         },
       22:{
           'question':"Dandia’ is a popular dance of?",
           'a':'Jaipur',
           'b':'Gujarat',
           'c':'Madhyapradesh',
           'd':'Mizoram',
           'ans':'Gujarat',
           'marks':1,
           'level':'easy',
           'std':3,
           'sub':'GK'
         },
       23:{

           'question':"The capital of Kosala kingdom was?",
           'a':'New Delhi',
           'b':'Ayodhya',
           'c':'Hazipur',
           'd':'Mizoram',
           'ans':'Ayodhya',
           'marks':1,
           'level':'easy',
           'std':3,
           'sub':'History'
         },
       24:{
           'question':"The Saka Era commenced in?",
           'a':'78ad',
           'b':'92ad',
           'c':'85ad',
           'd':'None of these',
           'ans':'78ad',
           'marks':1,
           'level':'easy',
           'std':3,
           'sub':'History'
         },
       25:{
           'question':"District Judges in a State are appointed by the?",
           'a':'Prime minister',
           'b':'Governor',
           'c':'Both a&b',
           'd':'None of these',
           'ans':'Governor',
           'marks':1,
           'level':'easy',
           'std':3,
           'sub':'History'
         }
    }
